Association of University and College Employees collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Association of University and College Employees collection
1974 - 1992
F-120
Q106643018
50 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Archives and Records Management Department
The University Archives acquires, preserves and makes available three categories of materials: (1) the official records of the University, including those created by the Board of Governors, Senate, University committees, faculties, departments and administrative offices; (2) materials documenting the wider University community; and (3) historical research collections that promote the teaching and research activities of the University.
The Archives was established within the University Library in 1968 when librarian Liisa Fagerlund was appointed University Archivist on a half-time basis. She continued in this post until 1975 when she left the University. From 1975 to 1978, the Archives functioned within the Special Collections division of the Library. Archival duties were carried out by various library staff members. In 1978, the University Archives was established as a separate administrative unit outside of the Library. Donald Baird, recently retired as University Librarian, became University Archivist and held this position until his retirement in 1990. Jim Ross served as University Archivist from 1991 to 1993, and was succeeded by Ian Forsyth in 1994.
When the Archives was a function of the University Library, the University Archivist reported to the University Librarian. When the Archives was established as a separate administrative unit, the University Archivist reported directly to the University President. The reporting structure changed in 1986 when the University Archivist reported to the Vice-President, Research/Information Systems; in 1990, when the University Archivist reported to the Associate Vice-President, Academic; and in 1996, when the University Archivist reported to the Registrar/Dean of Students.
published
Full
Revised
Title of fonds based on its contents.
Collection consists of records reflecting the administration, organization and activities of AUCE #2 as well as AUCE's provincial organization. Includes constitution, by-laws, articles of agreement, contracts, financial statements, reports, correspondence, memoranda, ephemera, newsletters, handbooks, and bulletins.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Archives and Records Management Department; Association of University and College Employees, Local 2; Labour
Archives staff accumulated the collection from a number of different sources including Reva Clavier (a former member of AUCE's executive), the Office of the Dean of Arts, the Office of the Vice-President, Administration and the University Archives. It is not always clear which records originate from which source, although annotations and stamps on specific documents reveal the source for some records.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Please consult the inventories of the Simon Fraser University Staff Association fonds, F-119, the Heather Raven fonds, F-22, the Michael Irwin fonds, F-121 and series F-82-1 of the Ellen Frank fonds, F-82.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Administration and organization files, 1974 - 1992; F-120-1; 20 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the administration and organization of the Association of University and College Employees, Local #2. Records reflect AUCE's executive and general meetings, elections, financial statements, and various committees such as the strike support committee and the grievance committee. Includes constitution, by-laws, articles of agreement, contracts, reports, minutes of meetings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, and ephemera.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Articles of Agreement, 1974 - 1976; F-120-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Articles of Agreement, 1976 - 1978; F-120-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
    Pending review
  - Articles of Agreement, 1978 - 1980; F-120-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1980 - 1982; F-120-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1983; F-120-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1983 - 1985; F-120-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1985 - 1986; F-120-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1986 - 1988; F-120-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1988 - 1990; F-120-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1990 - 1992; F-120-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - By-laws and Provincial Constitution, 1983; F-120-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - TSSU Agreement (AUCE Local #6), 1982; F-120-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Executive meetings, 1975 - 1976; F-120-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - General membership meetings, 1974 - 1979; F-120-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Financial Statements, 1984 - 1990; F-120-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - AUCE Divisions, 1974 - 1980; F-120-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Affiliation - Labour code / Provincial policies, 1975 - 1980; F-120-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 120-1)
  - Elections, 1975 - 1983; F-120-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Elections, 1978; F-120-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Statements by Executive candidates, 1982; F-120-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Contract Committee, 1974 - 1975; F-120-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Contract Committee, 1976 - 1977; F-120-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Contract Committee, 1978; F-120-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - General committees - minutes, 1976 - 1979; F-120-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Grievance committees - minutes, 1975 - 1976; F-120-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Strike Committee, 1974 - 1976; F-120-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Strike Support Committee, 1978; F-120-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
- Correspondence, memoranda, and ephemera, 1974 - 1992; F-120-2; 10 cm of textual records
  Series consists of correspondence, memoranda and ephemera created and disseminated by the Association of University and College Employees. Records reflect a wide range of subjects relevant to the union, including labour disputes, salaries, union affiliation, contract negotiations, and the like.
  - General correspondence and papers, 1975 - 1981; F-120-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Correspondence, 1977 - 1979; F-120-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Memoranda, 1974 - 1977; F-120-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Memoranda, 1974 - 1978; F-120-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Memoranda, 1976 - 1983; F-120-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Memoranda, 1984 - 1988; F-120-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 120-2)
  - Memoranda, 1988; F-120-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Memoranda, 1989; F-120-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Ephemera - strike, 1975; F-120-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Ephemera - strike, 1978; F-120-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Ephemera, 1990 - 1992; F-120-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
- AUCE Provincial organization files, 1974 - 1981; F-120-3; 4 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records reflecting AUCE's Provincial organization. Includes convention agenda, Provincial candidates' statements, resolutions, newsletters and ephemera.
  - Annual Conventions, 1974 - 1981; F-120-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - AUCE Affiliation Bulletin, 1979 - 1980; F-120-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - AUCE Provincial Dispatch, 1979 - 1980; F-120-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - AUCE Provincial News, 1976 - 1981; F-120-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
- Publications, 1974 - 1991; F-120-4; 17 cm of textual records
  Series consists of various publications from AUCE. Includes newsletters, handbooks, and bulletins.
  - AUCE Anchor, 1974 - 1975; F-120-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - AUCE Anchor, 1976 - 1977; F-120-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - AUCE Anchor, 1978 - 1980; F-120-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Bulletins, 1981 - 1983; F-120-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 120-3)
  - Bulletin Board, 1979 - 1983; F-120-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Bulletin Board, 1984 - 1987; F-120-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Bulletin Board, 1988 - 1990; F-120-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Bulletin Board, 1991; F-120-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - AUCE 2 Campus Directory, 1981; F-120-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - 2AUCE, 1979 - 1989; F-120-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Union Women Speak, 1976; F-120-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Presentation to SFU support staff, 1989; F-120-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 120-4)
  - Issue sheets - CUPE, 1989 - 1991; F-120-4-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 120-4)